<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Awakening Begins!</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai</link>
	<description>Day The Earth Stood Still</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 12:00:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.4</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/cropped-saturn-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Awakening Begins!</title>
	<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Pie remains the same; it’s the bigger piece everyone is fighting for.</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/11/29/fight-for-the-indian-telecom-subscriber-base/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/11/29/fight-for-the-indian-telecom-subscriber-base/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[joydeep]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airtel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BSNL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telecom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telecom subscribers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vodaphone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=998</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Fight for the Indian Telecom Subscriber Base:  Airtel ® , Vodafone ® and BSNL®  are some of the largest mobile service providers in the country. Today, if we visit any of their web sites you will be lured to sign up or subscribe to one of their plans/services. On the contrary and just out of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/11/29/fight-for-the-indian-telecom-subscriber-base/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Pie remains the same; it’s the bigger piece everyone is fighting for."</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 style="text-align: right;"><span style="color: #ffcc00;"><strong>Fight for the Indian Telecom Subscriber Base: </strong></span></h4>
<p>Airtel ® , Vodafone ® and BSNL®  are some of the largest mobile service providers in the country.</p>
<p>Today, if we visit any of their web sites you will be lured to sign up or subscribe to one of their plans/services. On the contrary and just out of curiosity, I visited BSNL site to check what they offered. To my surprise, and I spent about 30 mins and I am still confused as I was before visiting their site.<span id="more-998"></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The world is moving to a more intuitive way of attracting and retaining customers, technology immensely used to find and capture more customers.<span style="font-size: 1rem;">This attitude to acquire and retain customers is vividly visible in the way you customize your site, physical or internet, that is the face of the organization. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem;">Take a look at any of the Pizza site or e-Tailing site and you will be amazed on how seriously they take on the site visits and spend loads to make the first impression.</span></p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;">Agony of common citizen</h6>
<p>Today, I was checking on ways to cut my phone bill. I then thought of BSNL for some cost efficient plans. After spending about 30 mins I still don’t have an answer to what I want.</p>
<p>Infact, this organization has taken bureaucracy to the ultimate level. I tried to port my number to BSNL couple of years ago and almost got tears in my eyes on the way they carefully preserved dumb legacy &#8211; quite an art. I instantly decided, quicker than the 2 min noodle, not to switch.</p>
<p>Lets take a quick look at our postal service as well. I saw some great transformation in USPS and Canada Post despite fierce competition from some global players. Companies there, public and/or private, without any hesitance use their service and have high respect as well.</p>
<p>The game has changed so the game plan has to change too. You cannot sustain, unless for eternity, plan to survive on the tax payers money.</p>
<p>Getting new customers don’t require any crystal ball gazing. Not anymore! Its more of a science, science of knowing and understanding your customers.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 18pt; color: #ff0000;">BSNL ® are you even aware</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 18pt; color: #ff0000;">                              of the competition ?</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/11/29/fight-for-the-indian-telecom-subscriber-base/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Multi Generation Plan &#8211; (MGP)</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/05/31/multi-generation-plan-mgp/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/05/31/multi-generation-plan-mgp/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 08:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[joydeep]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disruptive Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Multi Generation Product Plan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=982</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8211; Multi Generation Plan (MGP) Turn on my laptop and the first thing I do is open my safari browser and type in Google.com and that is how the day begins. Whether you like it or not Google Inc. has invaded all the spaces we ever called private. Be it a search in your browser &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/05/31/multi-generation-plan-mgp/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Multi Generation Plan &#8211; (MGP)"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 style="text-align: right;">&#8211; Multi Generation Plan (MGP)</h6>
<p>Turn on my laptop and the first thing I do is open my <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Safari_(web_browser)">safari browser</a> and type in Google.com and that is how the day begins. Whether you like it or not <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google">Google Inc.</a> has invaded all the spaces we ever called private. Be it a search in your browser using laptop or handheld devices or that early morning jogging or that quite yoga session &#8211; your activities are statisticized.<span id="more-982"></span></p>
<p>Google knows everything you do, everywhere you go and now everything you even talk. The position Google enjoys now isn&#8217;t by fluke or by chance. They would have prepared for it for years and have a vision for the next x years. What they are doing it just inching towards the vision. It’s their vision that makes them so competitive and forward looking. That is why they come up with such innovative products and their consumers love them.</p>
<p>Here is the graph that will show how they have done and the future looks even brighter.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-979 size-full" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/1.png" alt="Multi Generation Plan" width="746" height="532" srcset="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/1.png 746w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/1-300x214.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></p>
<p>Google has been able to maintain their core products so that they don&#8217;t lose focus on what made them and built on the same customer base. It has been a great run and don’t see them slowing down anytime soon.</p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;">For other companies to catch up they need to:</h6>
<p><strong>1 Create a brand</strong>: Google Inc. has a great brand recall value. Like my day starts with Google.com and not with any other search engines. Other brands need to be able to create a brand like Google.Inc. For that you need to have a MGP (Multi Generation Plan).</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-980" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/2.jpg" alt="Multi Generation Plan" width="600" height="402" /></p>
<p><strong>2 Disruptive marketing</strong>: like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patanjali_Ayurved">Patanjali</a> in India have brought some of the major <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast-moving_consumer_goods">FMCG</a> companies on their knees. I know it is not an apple-to-apple comparison, however, there has to be a way to offer more to your customers that will distract them from choosing the obvious. Again, this has be linked to the MGP. (Image source: Quora)</p>
<p><strong>3 Innovation</strong>: Continue to innovate and offer customer what they want and you will never run out of market. Gone are the days when<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Ford"> Sir Henry Ford</a> said &#8220;<em>A customer can have a car painted any color he wants as long as it’s black</em>&#8220;, you need to be able to offer products that are customizable as per every individual customer, sounds ridiculous, that is where Google is heading to.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oath_Inc.">Oath</a>&#8221; a concentrated effort by Yahoo and AOL (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verizon_Communications">Verizon owned company</a>) seems to be making some waves, well its too early to say how they are going to shape up. Their revenue projection looks healthy; however, they have some steep competition from dynamic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook">FB</a> and the Google giant.</p>
<p>The fun is about to begin as the competition is getting intense. This competition is healthy and does not really matter who wins, we will still be the King’s &amp; Queen’s &#8211; that is wicked <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/05/31/multi-generation-plan-mgp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remix and Recreated &#8211; Who cares (Modern Music)</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/05/22/modern-music/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/05/22/modern-music/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 09:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[joydeep]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music remix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Next-gen music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=950</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Rise of remixes! On my way to a training assignment this morning, I tune into a radio station for some morning motivation and some foot tapping music. I loved the mix of numbers that was being played throughout my trip to my workplace. If you hear carefully you will observe 4 out of 10 songs &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/05/22/modern-music/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Remix and Recreated &#8211; Who cares (Modern Music)"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 style="text-align: right;">Rise of remixes!</h6>
<p>On my way to a training assignment this morning, I tune into a radio station for some morning motivation and some foot tapping music. I loved the mix of numbers that was being played throughout my trip to my workplace.</p>
<p>If you hear carefully you will observe 4 out of 10 songs created these days are “sort of” remix or recreated. These music were blockbusters during their era and certainly some of the best numbers. I know they had nothing that needed to be corrected for that time.</p>
<p><span id="more-950"></span></p>
<p>Question is! Are the modern day composers spoiling the originality of those numbers?</p>
<p>Well no not really, yes they are much modern and tosses with some fresh masalas just to suit the taste of the newer generation. Is it wrong? I strongly feel no as this is one great way to keep alive some great music/composition. These were music created during 60’s, some great compositions. Its unfortunate that those are slowly fading and there will be time when these will be completely forgotten.</p>
<p>I am personally not a great fan of remix or recreation. It feels great to sing along a recreated song with my little one &#8211; even he accepts it well.</p>
<p>Its fun to witness how music is evolving these days. For good or bad these great music will stay alive for next few generations and that is so comforting.</p>
<p>Are they running out of creative juice? Oh wait, who really cares as long as you have some good music to sooth or prep you. Lastly reminds you of your times &#8211; you sure know what I am talking about <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/05/22/modern-music/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reema and The Gnomes</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/04/20/reema-and-the-gnomes/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/04/20/reema-and-the-gnomes/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 19:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Niharika]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairy tail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gnomes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magic and alchemy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Short Kid Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=920</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8211; Beautiful story of Reema. Reema was a poor girl who lived in a small tent all by herself. The only way to earn her money was to go to the nearby factory called &#8216; Cadbury &#8216; who&#8217;s owner was very mean and rude. Reema went to work as usual. Miss Parkison, the factory owner &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/04/20/reema-and-the-gnomes/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Reema and The Gnomes"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 style="text-align: center;">&#8211; Beautiful story of Reema.</h6>
<p>Reema was a poor girl who lived in a small tent all by herself. The only way to earn her money was to go to the nearby factory called &#8216; Cadbury &#8216; who&#8217;s owner was very mean and rude. Reema went to work as usual. Miss Parkison, the factory owner made Reema and her fellow coworkers stand in a line. &#8220;So?&#8221; Asked Miss Parkison with a sickly sweet smile. She looked around as though expecting someone to shout &#8216; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/April_Fools%27_Day">APRIL FOOLS</a>! &#8216; . And in a blink of an eye she roared “get to work!!!” and she walked away. <span id="more-920"></span></p>
<p>Everyone but the supervisor scrambled to their seats. Tasha &amp; Rohit, Reema&#8217;s best friends complained to her as though she was their leader and gave her a headache. Reema returned home at 3:25 am and fell asleep immediately. A tiny gnome walked over to Reema&#8217;s bag and sniffed it. Slowly more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gnome">Gnomes</a> came and began to sniff it, hopeful for some food. They found some chocolates and gnawed it in an instant. But they did not know that the chocolates were for Reema&#8217;s lunch.</p>
<p>The next day , Reema opened her bag for her chocolates but instead they were replaced by wrappers by the Gnomes. “oh well, if someone has stolen it then it&#8217;s alright; I can try to get some more for myself.&#8221; Hearing this leader of the Gnomes was very pleased with Reema. She had forgiven the Gnomes even if she was hungry.</p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;">Cosmic blessings!</h6>
<p>&#8220;Oi! Every gnome, listen to me. “He told the other gnomes. “Since that Reema girl forgave us, we have to help her in return. Any ideas? “Several hands shot up in the air.”Yes? Sir- er?&#8221; He asked a funny looking gnome with a wooden leg, an eye patch, a chunk of his nose missing and a silly Red hat with a stuffed elephant on top. “I am Cadogan . I ain&#8217;t gonna be helpin much but ah thinks we should help er with er works. Yeh agrees with meh? Eh?&#8221; &#8221; Err&#8230;everygnome in favour of sir Cadogan, raise your hands.&#8221; Said the leader.</p>
<p>A 3/4 of the group raised their hands. &#8220;Yeh see? Ah am great! Yeh ain&#8217;t gonna change the idea. Got tha leader chap? Who needs this meeting today. Every gnome ain&#8217;t need it. Yeh leaders.&#8221;Shouted Cadogan. “Miss Jean, my dear secretary, tell me, where does Miss Reema work&#8221; Asked the leader. At the Cadbury factory down Street, Chapman road ,#307,sweet lime layout. “Replied the Secretary as though bored.” Righto, Jean “cried the leader cheerfully.  It was clear that he thought Reema an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angel">angel</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-923 aligncenter" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_407-290x300.png" alt="Reema and The Gnomes" width="290" height="300" srcset="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_407-290x300.png 290w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_407-768x795.png 768w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_407.png 897w" sizes="(max-width: 290px) 100vw, 290px" /><br />
REEMA</h6>
<p>He then said “come on! The faster we go the faster we get there!&#8221;</p>
<p>**********************************************************************************************</p>
<p>Reema came home as exhausted as she had ever felt before. She still had extra work to do but accidently forgot to do it and now the factory was closed. She had to go and face her doom sent by Miss Parkison tomorrow. But now she couldn&#8217;t know when was tomorrow for she fell asleep.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-922 aligncenter" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_205-133x300.png" alt="Reema and The Gnomes" width="133" height="300" srcset="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_205-133x300.png 133w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_205-456x1024.png 456w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_205.png 513w" sizes="(max-width: 133px) 100vw, 133px" /></p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;">EXHAUSTED LEVEL 4</h6>
<p>***********************************************************************************************</p>
<p>Meanwhile, at the Cadbury factory down Street, the Gnomes were at work. “This is tiring&#8221; complained about gnome named Dean. &#8220;Don&#8217;t worry, Dean at least we are good at making chocolate.&#8221; Said a sympathetic female gnome. “Sigh. You are right Sara&#8221;. And he continued.  The leader was bustling around instructing and helping. “oh, come on Cadogan. Help just a little. &#8221; &#8221; Ah ain&#8217;t helpin no gnome if ah don&#8217;t get nothings, fudge&#8221; and soon 7:00 came and the Gnomes left the factory.</p>
<p>***********************************************************************************************</p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;">The Punishment</h6>
<p>Reema was ready for this. It was her doom. She was not going to survive. With a sinking heart, she left her tent house and cycled towards the factory. Miss Parkison was waiting for her. “I seem to have just heard from Emilia that before leaving she found your work INCOMPLETE.  I hate incomplete work, Reema and you seem to have put a toe out of line.</p>
<p>Punishment: a hundred lashes on your stomach and back. Now, excuse me, I have to see your work. A minute later the police arrived. &#8220;Hey, little girl. Are you Reema Kapoor? ““Of course &#8220;replied Reema” well congrats you get one billion dollars and $90000000 as extra young lady.&#8221; “W-w-what?! You m-must have made a m-mistake.&#8221; Stammered Reema. &#8220;Nah, go on, Miss Parkison is under arrest. An odd little bloke came to my office 15 minutes ago and told me everything, now go and take this:</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-924 aligncenter" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_193-231x300.png" alt="Reema and The Gnomes" width="231" height="300" srcset="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_193-231x300.png 231w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_193-768x996.png 768w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_193-789x1024.png 789w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Unicorn_193.png 1185w" sizes="(max-width: 231px) 100vw, 231px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">CUTE       LITTLE     BLONDE      CAT</p>
<p>&#8220;Gee, thank you officer, will my friends be alright too?” Asked Reema. &#8220;Yes&#8221;</p>
<p>While walking to the electronic shop, Reema was shocked to be told that her work was complete? But who did it? thought Reema. The Gnomes were planning to tell Reema that answer. But that is another story!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">THE END</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/04/20/reema-and-the-gnomes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Silence! A precious feeling….</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/04/11/silence-a-precious-feeling/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/04/11/silence-a-precious-feeling/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 10:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mukta sadana]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy & Spiritualism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Introspect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silence]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=909</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Why are you so afraid of silence? Silence! A precious feeling. We all run away from silence! But then again we want silence when we are troubled or when we need to do deep thinking. Why? Because we know, we will get answers if we remain silent for a while and just think about the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/04/11/silence-a-precious-feeling/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Silence! A precious feeling…."</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 style="text-align: right;">Why are you so afraid of silence?</h6>
<p>Silence! A precious feeling. We all run away from silence! But then again we want silence when we are troubled or when we need to do deep thinking. Why? Because we know, we will get answers if we remain silent for a while and just think about the situation.</p>
<p>Instead of waiting to be in a situation to be silent, why can&#8217;t we start our day observing silence for 10 minutes every day before we start our day? To <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Introspection">introspect</a> ourselves and to plan our day ahead!<span id="more-909"></span></p>
<p>It might not be possible to do so at the start of the day, and then do it towards the end of the day. When you are done with your chores of the day. Switch off the idiot box, keep your phone away and just be your own. Analysing your day, planning the next day, and thinking about good things happened through the day.</p>
<p>Doing this is same as meditation. It will make you calmer, sharper and will enable you to make good decisions rather than hasty decisions. A calm mind helps you make better sections and grow personally and professionally.</p>
<p>Whosoever said Silence is Golden Knew the true essence of Silence.</p>
<p><a href="http://lapizlazulai.com/conversation-with-self/">Recommended reading </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/04/11/silence-a-precious-feeling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversation with Self</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/03/01/conversation-with-self/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/03/01/conversation-with-self/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 17:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mukta sadana]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Awareness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[De-stress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mindfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[positive]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=896</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8211; Conversation with Self How does one analyse what they want? What do they want to achieve and what is stopping them from achieving their dreams and goals? Nobody comes forward to tell them all this. Nobody guides them. All this happens because that one person has a conversation with oneself. A conversation where he/she &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/03/01/conversation-with-self/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Conversation with Self"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 style="text-align: right;">&#8211; Conversation with Self</h6>
<p>How does one analyse what they want? What do they want to achieve and what is stopping them from achieving their dreams and goals? Nobody comes forward to tell them all this. Nobody guides them.<span id="more-896"></span></p>
<p>All this happens because that one person has a conversation with oneself. A conversation where he/she knows what is their weakness and what is their strength! The person then starts evaluating the situation and take necessary steps.</p>
<p>It is important to have conversation with oneself and nobody knows you better than you yourself. Others may show you the way but whether that way will take you to your destination or not that is your decision.</p>
<p>A path of your life is carved by you alone.</p>
<p>A path of your journey has to be taken by you alone.</p>
<p>Have a self-talk to visualize your journey &#8230;Your path!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/03/01/conversation-with-self/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why the World Doesn&#8217;t Need Photographers</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/15/why-the-world-doesnt-need-photographers/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/15/why-the-world-doesnt-need-photographers/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 12:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lapiz Lazulai]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photographer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=855</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8211; All the technique in the world doesn&#8217;t compensate for the inability to notice. Truth is nobody is interested in seeing your photographs. Nobody cares about the work that you are doing as a photographer. Nobody cares about anybody&#8217;s work. You could take that a step further and say &#8216;you know the world really does &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/15/why-the-world-doesnt-need-photographers/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Why the World Doesn&#8217;t Need Photographers"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">&#8211; All the technique in the world doesn&#8217;t compensate for the inability to notice.</span></h6>
<p>Truth is nobody is interested in seeing your photographs. Nobody cares about the work that you are doing as a photographer. Nobody cares about anybody&#8217;s work. You could take that a step further and say &#8216;you know the world really does not need any more photographers&#8217;. We have plenty, they are over-saturated, we do not need any more photographers, musicians, actors, writers we certainly do not need any more films produced. We are over-saturated there is too much stuff out there.<span id="more-855"></span></p>
<p>This isn’t necessarily a bitter truth but the world does need work that matters. Our survival as a culture is dependent on work that means something. The role arts have always played in our culture even has changed a lot over the years whether that is a &#8216;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._K._Rowling">J. K. Rowling&#8217;</a> novel, whether that&#8217;s paintings on a cave wall, whether that’s many years later a Beethoven symphony, whether that&#8217;s the Sistine Chapel these are things that significantly matter in the history of the world.</p>
<p>We live in very complicated times. There are a lot of issues that if you consider that art plays a role in our lives that makes us think it creates awareness, sometimes it just makes us feel better about ourselves. It creates positivity. It creates many different kinds of energy that help us deal with who we are and where we&#8217;re going as people.</p>
<h6 style="text-align: left;">&#8211; Photography of the future</h6>
<p>Now those are two different things ‘work that matters’ and ‘nobody wants to look at your photographs’. Point is that if you&#8217;re going to shoot just for you the truth is that there&#8217;s plenty of stuff out there.  Most people will not become known. A lot of people remain unknown and that&#8217;s just how it works. Work that matters is important and that&#8217;s what you should be striving to do. It is not a popularity contest; it is creating something that means something.</p>
<p>Photography in the next 5, 10 or 20 years is going to look very different. With mobile stuff with the internet with social media and those are just barely starting to mature. People see more images in a day that are displayed on a computer screen than they do in print or on a gallery wall.</p>
<p>To figure out what is that work that is going to matter. What are you trying to say as an artist. How do you go about doing and that is the challenge. It is not easy. It is not something you are going to discover in a couple minutes, an hour, weekend or even in a couple years. Sometimes it&#8217;s something that you&#8217;re constantly pursuing and working towards. It is important and like I said sure nobody wants to see my work or your work. Nobody cares, therefore we need work that makes a difference! We need work that means something!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/15/why-the-world-doesnt-need-photographers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intel&#8217;s smart glasses – that isn&#8217;t a Borg headgear!</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/10/intels-smart-glasses-that-isnt-a-borg-headgear/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/10/intels-smart-glasses-that-isnt-a-borg-headgear/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 18:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lapiz Lazulai]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SmartGlass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vaunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wearable Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=848</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[-The idea is fancy and revolutionary. Intel’s smart glasses ‘Vaunt’ is completely different from what you are expecting, weighs about 50 grams and designed to do just one thing, show simple, basic information in one of the eyes. It has a red monochrome projector that shines an image on a holographic mirror. Light then bounces &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/10/intels-smart-glasses-that-isnt-a-borg-headgear/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Intel&#8217;s smart glasses – that isn&#8217;t a Borg headgear!"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h5 style="text-align: right;">-The idea is fancy and revolutionary.</h5>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intel">Intel’s</a> smart glasses ‘Vaunt’ is completely different from what you are expecting, weighs about 50 grams and designed to do just one thing, show simple, basic information in one of the eyes. It has a red monochrome projector that shines an image on a holographic mirror. Light then bounces directly into the viewers eyeball. Best part is that if you are not looking slightly down at the display, it completely disappears.<span id="more-848"></span></p>
<p>There is no camera, it is meant to be non-intrusive, not annoying in social situations. Vaunt glasses are a prototype project from Intel&#8217;s new devices group. Later in 2018 developers are going to be able to start using them. These glasses need to be fitted to the wearer eyes&#8217; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pupillary_distance">interpupillary distance</a> so that the display can line up to eyeball.</p>
<p>It uses a type of laser called a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vertical-cavity_surface-emitting_laser">VCSEL (Vertical-cavity surface-emitting laser)</a> – it is a low power <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laser_safety">class one laser</a> &amp; harmless to the human eye. A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holographic_grating">holographic grating</a> is embedded in the lens to reflect the correct <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wavelength">wavelengths</a> back to the eye. The image is painted into the back of the wearer’s retina. If the wearer wears prescription glasses then it is used for looking at the world but not for the image. You can have terrible vision and still see bright, sharp, clear image that looks like it comes from Infinity.</p>
<p>Intel is also introducing a level of behavioral  A.I. to these glasses, a system that allows to figure out what to show you when. Intel glasses currently represents the most promising version of smart glasses that are in the market &amp; is in the very early stage of development &amp; like mobile phones this has the potential to become the next big thing!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/10/intels-smart-glasses-that-isnt-a-borg-headgear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teleportation &#8211; Will It Ever Be Possible</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/02/teleportation-will-it-ever-be-possible/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/02/teleportation-will-it-ever-be-possible/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 20:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lapiz Lazulai]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sci-Fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beam me up scotty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Captain Kirk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teleportation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=835</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8211; Metaphysics of Teleportation One of the deepest theological questions at the merger where physics and philosophy collide. In the present time, we can only teleport photons, particles of light and atoms like caesium and rubidium. However, in the coming years we do expect to be able to teleport molecules, maybe water, carbon dioxide. After &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/02/teleportation-will-it-ever-be-possible/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Teleportation &#8211; Will It Ever Be Possible"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 style="text-align: right;"><strong>&#8211; Metaphysics of Teleportation</strong></h4>
<p>One of the deepest theological questions at the merger where physics and philosophy collide. In the present time, we can only teleport <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photon">photons</a>, particles of light and atoms like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caesium">caesium</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rubidium">rubidium</a>. However, in the coming years we do expect to be able to teleport molecules, maybe water, carbon dioxide. After that who knows? Maybe even <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNA">DNA</a>, maybe organic molecules.<span id="more-835"></span></p>
<p>Now to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teleportation">teleport</a> a human raises ethical dilemma, because the original human body has to be destroyed in the process of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum">quantum</a> teleportation. Therefore, if <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_T._Kirk">Captain Kirk</a>, zap himself across the room, you have now seen Captain Kirk die. You have seen his atoms fall apart, but here is this other Captain Kirk on the other side of the room who has the same bad jokes, who has the same character, all the personality quirks as the original Captain Kirk.</p>
<p>So the imposter says, &#8220;No, I&#8217;m real. I have the memories, the personality, and the quirks. I am Captain Kirk&#8221;. Well you just saw the original die and if you believe in a soul that soul went to heaven or maybe the other place, but that person is dead, so who is this imposter over there? <img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-839" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/download-300x168.jpg" alt="Teleportation - Will It Ever Be Possible " width="300" height="168" />Does the imposter have a soul? So it raises the question are we nothing but information? Is the soul, the essence of who we are, nothing but information? All we can say, it is physically possible to teleport an entire human being across the room or maybe onto Mars. It is physically possible to do that and it raises a valid question. What happened to the soul if your original copy died and somebody out there has all your memories? What does that mean? Answer is we don&#8217;t know.</p>
<p>In a little over a century, humankind has advanced from an uncertain new understanding of the behaviour of electrons at the atomic scale to reliably teleporting them across a room. What new technical mastery of such phenomena might we have in 1,000, or even 10,000 years? Only time and space will tell.</p>
<p>In the meanwhile! Beam me up SCOTTY!!!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-836 size-medium" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/StartrekKirkbeamwatermaek-300x168.jpg" alt="Teleportation - Will It Ever Be Possible " width="300" height="168" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/02/02/teleportation-will-it-ever-be-possible/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>12 Strong Movie Reaction</title>
		<link>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/01/26/12-strong-movie-reaction/</link>
				<comments>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/01/26/12-strong-movie-reaction/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 07:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lapiz Lazulai]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hollywood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[12 strong movie review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9/11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Hemsworth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Horse Soldiers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lapizlazulai.com/?p=814</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8211; A five point five pointer &#160; A film starring Chris Hemsworth and Michael Shannon, 12 Strong’s narrative focuses on the first Special Forces team who are deployed to Afghanistan after 9/11. In an attempt to take down the Taliban, the team must work with an Afghan warlord while under the leadership of their new &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/01/26/12-strong-movie-reaction/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "12 Strong Movie Reaction"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>&#8211; A five point five pointer</h4>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A film starring <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Hemsworth">Chris Hemsworth</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Shannon">Michael Shannon</a>, 12 Strong’s narrative focuses on the first Special Forces team who are deployed to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Afghanistan">Afghanistan</a> after <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/September_11_attacks">9/11.</a> In an attempt to take down the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taliban">Taliban</a>, the team must work with an Afghan warlord while under the leadership of their new captain, Mitch played by Chris Hemsworth.<span id="more-814"></span> Story is based on book entitled <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/12_Strong">Horse Soldiers</a>, which tells the story of CIA officers and U.S. Special Forces sent to Afghanistan immediately after 9/11. I really like the poster for this movie. It’s simple yet colorful but engaging.</p>
<p>Did I like it?Is it good?Is it AMAZING? IT IS………okay.<img class="alignright size-full wp-image-820" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-2-4.jpg" alt="12 Strong movie reaction" width="225" height="225" srcset="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-2-4.jpg 225w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-2-4-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-2-4-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></p>
<p>The problem that this movie has is that it’s slow moving. The story moves from one scene to the next without truly taking the time to allow the audience to absorb and feel the moment. This makes the movie feel dense, in that you don’t get a true understanding of these characters. You don’t get a full understanding of who they are. You do get a brief backstory of some of them in cast and their families, such as Chris Hemsworth, Michael Shannon, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Pe%C3%B1a">Michael Pena’s</a> characters, however, it’s not enough to create a foundation to understand who these characters are and understand why or how they’re responding to certain situations.</p>
<h6>-Lack substance behind writing</h6>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-822 alignleft" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-3-3-300x136.jpg" alt="12 Strong movie reaction" width="300" height="136" srcset="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-3-3-300x136.jpg 300w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-3-3.jpg 334w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />This is not due to the fault of the actors, but the lack of substance behind the writing. This is not a terribly written movie, but the film suffers from the fact that the story always moves the characters, but the characters rarely move or progress the story. I didn’t hate this movie and although there have been quite a few 911 movies; this was definitely a story that world needs to know.</p>
<p>These men were deployed to Afghanistan literally right after the events of 911. You hear the events on the news and BOOM these men are out there fighting. In that regard, the movie does this story Justice. You can appreciate what these men are going through; these are the men you heard about on the news without truly knowing what was going on during the war. Although the score is nothing special, the visuals are quite good.<img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-823" src="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-1-3-300x129.jpg" alt="12 Strong movie reaction" width="300" height="129" srcset="https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-1-3-300x129.jpg 300w, https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/images-1-3.jpg 343w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>While the actors may not have many moments to shine in, the performances were still quite good, and the American heroism does shine at points in this movie. It&#8217;s unfortunate that some of these other factors weighted it down! With that being said it’s time for a final rating. Alright I’m going to give 12 Strong a 5.5 at best.</p>
<p><iframe width="525" height="295" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P-X19IxfVEE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://lastspacefighter.github.io/lapizlazulai/2018/01/26/12-strong-movie-reaction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
